JONATHAN LASCAZE

m: +603.921.0278 Lascaze.j@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jonathanlascaze

Github: github.com/jlasc



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Vision-driven leader in finance and in higher education with a proven record of data management skills, banking operations, metrics-driven university admission processes, and staff management expertise. Dedicated web engineer who is persistently creating and learning new technologies to maximize productivity, and quickly respond to the changing needs of the industry.

PROJECTS

Weather2DoIt

Persistent to-do list connected to Meetup API and Weather API using responsive design and user authentication HTML/CSS, JS, Firebase, API, User Auth https://github.com/JLasc/Weather2DoIt

Bamazon CLI App

Node & MySQL faux-amazon store database with user, manager, and supervisor views to manipulate data in DB JS, Node, Vagrant, MySQL https://qithub.com/JLasc/Bamazon

Liri Bot

Node bot capable of submitting user requests to three APIs, and reading commands from word document JS, Spotify, BandsInTown, OMDB https://github.com/JLasc/Liri-Bot

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN DATA ANALYTICS, 2021

Southern New Hampshire University, Manchester, NH

CODING BOOT CAMP - MERN STACK, 2018

University of New Hampshire, Manchester, NH

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN FINANCE & ECONOMICS, 2011

Southern New Hampshire University, Manchester, NH

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FINANCIAL AID SERVICES, SALEM, NH, 2018 TO 2019

FRONT END INTERN

- Assisted in design and developed front-end for organization client portal, utilizing Polymer, Immutable JS, Nuclear JS, Kubernetes, and Gulp
- Translated design team's UX wireframes and mockups into responsive, interactive features, using JavaScript and Polymer
- Coordinated with team to develop innovative solutions to cater to a wide audience
- Monitored and ensured high quality control on both designs and code for website

JONATHAN LASCAZE Page 2

SOUTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE UNIVERSITY, MANCHESTER, NH, 2014 TO 2018

GRADUATE TEAM LEAD

 Execute performance goals and standards as leader of a team focused on weekly, monthly, and yearly targets

- Evaluate employees based on standard expectations; implement coaching mechanisms and corrective action as required
- Implement training plans to ensure effective performance
- · Analyze statistical data and communicate results to management staff
- Perform inquiry resolution resulting from technical questions on SNHU degree programs and admissions processes
- Chair meetings to inform staff and to develop effective communications within and among teams
- Function as an active member of commencement activities for the University
- Communicate with appropriate University data to potential students, leading to acceptance and revenue growth
- Foster student support through the lifecycle of the admission process
- Facilitated mentorship training for experienced counselor to work with new admission counselors
- Supervised a team of up to eleven admission staff

ADMISSION COUNSELOR I & II

- Attended weekly group and individual meetings to evaluate progress on institutional and departmental goals
- Assisted new student enrollment through proactive communication upon inquiry
- Shaped the training and mentoring of new employees to create an overall positive student focus for the department
- Analyzed metrics associated with higher education admission initiatives and identified trends and best practices in the field

RBS/CITIZENS, NASHUA, NH, 2012 TO 2014

BANKER I

- Orchestrated a system for processing applications for loan-type products
- Conducted communications around securing new-to-bank clientele
- Completed regular professional development, including ongoing compliance training
- Transitioned qualified customers to appropriate divisions for financial review
- Opened personal and business banking accounts according to operational standards and policies

FIDELITY INVESTMENTS, MERRIMACK, NH, 2011 TO 2012

CUSTOMER SUPPORT SERVICES

- Expanded options and communications with clients, delivering expertise on retirement options and related services
- Delivered plan-specific guidance to customers, using up-to-date information and specifications for follow-up customer service
- Processed loans and withdrawals with excellent customer service
- Modified database information with pertinent updates and improvements
- Worked on a team and applied client services ethics to a philosophy of excellent customer service.

BEST BUY, NASHUA, NH, 2008 TO 2012

Front End Operation Team Lead

- Managed front-end associates who were responsible for registers and returns
- Provided guidance and mentorship on proper sales techniques and customer service
- Reconciled cash vault at end of each day
- Prepared weekly schedule

JONATHAN LASCAZE Page 3

Computer Sales / Apple Consultant

- Participated in revenue growth
- Provided customer support
- Generated leads for business teams

COMPUSA, NASHUA, NH, 2006 TO 2008

Sales Specialist

- Proactively assisted customers with store purchases
- Participated in monthly sales trainings